


c--
We had to wait outside in the corridor until our names were called
Go down here and the bathroom’s at the end of the corridor.
measures promoting local commerce and industry 促进地方工商业发展的措施
They were old army comrades.
He misses his comrades from his days in the army.


Condense the soup by boiling it for several minutes.
condense into  冷凝 
Steam condense into water when it cools

Would you like milk or cream in your coffee?	
the cream of sth  精英；精华；精髓
The students at this college are the cream of the crop (=the best of all).
cream sb/sth↔ˈoff 提取（精华）；选取（最好的人或物）；取走（某数额的金钱）
The best students were creamed off by the grammar schools.
traditional crafts like basket-weaving 工艺
an aircraft or spacecraft 飞行器；飞机；航天器；宇宙飞船；航天飞机

Common salt is a compound of sodium and chlorine.
be compounded of/from sth 
The DNA molecule is compounded from many smaller molecules.
脱氧核糖核酸分子是由许多更小的分子组成的。
compound sth (with sth)  混合；掺和；拌和
liquid soaps compounded with disinfectant
a degree certificate
The members left the council chamber

The pilot tried to land his crippled plane.
conscious of sth，conscious that 意识到
She's very conscious of the problems involved
I was vaguely conscious that I was being watched.
draw/pull/close the curtains
contradiction(between A and B)
His public speeches are in direct contradiction to his personal lifestyle
There is a contradiction between the two sets of figures


the government's latest economic crisis
He turned and curled the ball around the goalkeeper//他转身把球绕过守门员
The baby had dark eyes and dark curls.卷发

These clauses form part of the contract between buyer and seller.
to contract AIDS/a virus/a disease 感染
Glass contracts as it cools.收缩
She has contracted to work 20 hours a week.合同
to win/be awarded a contract to build a new school
I was on a three-year contract that expired last week.

They left under the cloak of darkness.
This is a matter of individual conscience (= everyone must make their own judgement about it) 个人良知

a city/county/borough/district council 委员会
Johann would creep into the gallery to listen to the singers.
Let's go home, I'm chilled to the bone (= very cold)
What does that mean in concrete terms? 具体来说意味着什么
his claim to the French crown
a chart showing last year’s sales
The album went straight into the charts at number 1.

The children craned forward to see what was happening
For ten years he had been her constant companion
None of the passengers and crew were injured.
----------------------------------------------
Italy's national coach
They went to Italy on a coach tour.

Careful consideration should be given to issues of health and safety.健康与安全的问题应该认真予以考虑。
They wanted to move to a warmer climate.
The police think the videotape may hold some vital clues to the identity of the killer

The sheets are 100% pure cotton
Many civil cases can be settled out of court 很多民事案件可以厅外解决
The snake coiled around the branches of the tree.
Her long hair was coiled up in a plait at the top of her head.

Richardson concluded from his studies that equality between the sexes is still a long way off
Each chapter concludes with a short summary.
1.收费
We have to make a small charge for refreshments.
Delivery is free of charge.
2.账单；记账
Would you like to put that on your charge?
‘Are you paying cash?’ ‘No, it'll be a charge.’记账吧
3.指控；指责
He will be sent back to England to face a charge of (= to be on trial for)armed robbery
4.主管
She has charge of the day-to-day running of the business
I'm leaving the school in your charge.
5.电
a positive/negative charge
正╱负电荷
6.猛冲
The bull put its head down and qcharged.
charge(at) sb/sth
We charged at the enemy.
我们向敌人发起冲锋。





a bag of cement

They want to cement a good working relationship between the government and trade unions.
The contempt he felt for his fellow students was obvious

coarse sand/salt/hair


Try to cultivate a more relaxed and positive approach to life//试着培养一种更积极的生活态度

The company has been successful in cultivating a very professional image.//树立专业的形象
a conjunction of :同时发生
in conjunction with ==> together with
.the conjunction of two events.两个事件的同时发生
The system is designed to be used in conjunction with a word processing program

a blackcurrant cordial
The talks were conducted in a cordial atmosphere


He choked on a piece of bread

You coward! What are you afraid of?
The right to speak freely is written into the Constitution of the United States
the genetic constitution of cells


a map and compass
corporation==> a large business company （大）公司
He works for a large American corporation.
The local community was shocked by the murders.

The girls in a class tend to have a civilizing influence on the boys
The infinite distances of space are too great for the human mind to comprehend
The two halves of the document did not correspond

Our correspondant in South Africa sent this report.
the charm of this small Southern city

The police collared him less than 20 minutes after the robbery//抓住
Johann would creep into the gallery to listen to the singers
Our baby is just starting to crawl.
She's always crawling to the boss.
crawl to sb 巴结某人
Fenella leaned forward, clasping her hands around her knees
The country was plunged into economic chaos
He collapsed with a heart attack while he was dancing
I thought that without me the whole project would collapse
The car coasted along until it stopped.//滑行

coast(through/to sth）不费吹灰之力成功

Many believe that poverty is a direct consequence of overpopulation
Two hundred people lost their jobs as adirect consequence of the merger.

the economic and social contrasts between the poor and the rich
There is an obvious contrast between the cultures of East and West
The birth rate for older women has declined, but, by contrast, births to teenage mothers have increased.
The composition of the group that is studied depends on the interests of the researcher
the composition of ...的成分
Martin starts by lightly sketching in the compositions for his paintings//马丁开始时，在他的绘画作品中略略画出草图

a piece/length of cord===>line 
the cliff edge/top
The law has been condemned as an attack on personal liberty//这项法律是对个人自由的侵犯
 She knew that society would condemn her for leaving her children
 The police cadet’s duties were confined to taking statements from the crowd.//被限制为

Keep the dog confined in a suitable travelling cage
the African National Congress
 The president has lost the support of Congress



He has just been commissioned (as a) pilot officer.//任命
a commission on human rights
You get a 10% commission on everything you sell

a wedding/marriage ceremony

In crude terms,the causes of mental illness seem to be of three main kinds.
 Stone decided to hold a contest to see who could write the best song

a cricket match/team/club/ball
a very conservative attitude to education
He was conservatively dressed in a dark business suit.
the continent 欧洲

We have no contemporary account of the battle (= written near the time that it happened


--------------------------------
•He wants to act in concert with other nations
[Listen]He coped quite well as manager while still captaining the team.
Local authorities have to cope with the problems of homelessness
Put some coal on the fire.
His landing was cushioned by the fresh snow that had fallen
Can’t you see the comedy of the situation
Canals were originally built for the carriage of coal.
This poses a threat to agriculture and the food chain, and consequently to human health
The warehouse was undergoing conversion into apartments.
Anne went to chase the dog out of the garden
.an informal agreement to put a ceiling on salaries...对工资封顶的非正式协议
sandwiches with the crusts cut off
The Soviet Union had been forced by circumstances to sign a pact with Nazi Germany
I know I can trust her in any circumstance

a comprehensive list of addresses

This book requires a great deal of concentration
There's been too much concentration of power in the hands of central authorities.
权力一直过多地集中在中央机构手中。

After lengthy talks the two sides finally reached a compromise
a compromise between government and opposition
The cracks (= faults)in the government's economic policy are already beginning to show.
Her lawyer made a statement outside the court.

The shadows concealed her as she crept up to the house.
Tim could barely conceal his disappointment.

The cat was clawing at the leg of the chair
the factory chimneys of an industrial landscape
He took the car without the owner’s consent
wildlife conservation
The agencies are working together to co-ordinate policy on food safety
  I couldn’t get my brain to function or coordinate my muscles
All this information can be conveyed in a simple diagram.
Colours like red convey a sense of energy and strength
The officials were eager to convince us of the safety of the nuclear reactors 
使我们确信原子反应堆是安全的

the circumference of the earth
the commercial heart of the city
the technology of modern civilization
Power is largely concentrated in the hands of a small elite.
The committee is comprised of representatives from both the public and private sectors
